We're finally back...
やっとついた
Hey, Waver.
おい ウェイバー
Where are you looking? Over here, over here.
どこを見てる こっちだ こっち
G-Grandpa!
お お爺さん 何やってんだよ
What are you doing?
Does it matter?
いいから いいから
ま お前も上がっておいで ちょっと話をしよう
You come up here too.
Let's talk for a while.
Talk?
話って 何でまた屋根の上で
Why do we have to talk on the roof?
お爺さん また今度にしない
Grandpa, can it wait?
Oh, don't be like that.
まあまあ そう言うな
He really likes you, boy.
ずいぶん気に入られとるじゃないか 坊主
あのな あれは僕の暗示にかかっているだ…
Listen, he's just under my spell-
まあ 行ってやれ
Well, go up anyway.
あの御老 何やら折り入って話がある様子ではないか
It looks like the old man has something important to tell you.
余はまあ その辺をぶらついて見張っておるから 安心せい
I'll wander about and patrol, so don't worry.
No need to hold back.
遠慮はいらん
遠慮っつうか
It's not that I'm holding back...
Utw
Presents
Will one last miracle come to pass?
あと一度だけ奇跡は起こるだろう
Ato ichido dake kiseki wa okoru darou
A gentle voice paints a twisted future
優しい声で描く歪んだ未来
Yasashii koe de egaku yuganda mirai
For the sake of a world where nobody will cry
もう誰も泣かない世界の為に
Mou dare mo nakanai sekai no tame ni
Before reaching the crimson-stained sky
紅く汚された空の何処にも
Akaku kegasareta sora no doko ni mo
My cries and prayers fade and disappear
届かず消える叫びと祈り
Todokazu kieru sakebi to inori
I can go on, abandoning all consolation
慰めは捨てて行ける
Nagusame wa sutete yukeru
The beautiful moonlight shines towards the beginning and vanishes
綺麗な月の光が始まりへと沈み行く
Kirei na tsuki no hikari ga hajimari e to shizumiyuku
Into the distance
その彼方へ
Sono kanata e
I'll continue to reach out as my eyes are gradually closed
閉ざされてく瞳でまだ遠くへ手を伸ばす
Tozasareteku hitomi de mada tooku e te wo nobasu
I believe in your sorrow
君の嘆きを 信じて
Kimi no nageki wo shinjite
This is the best place to get some sunlight early in the morning.
ここはな 朝一番で光を浴びるには最高の場所でなあ
Sit down.
まあ座れ
ほれ コーヒーも用意してある あったまるぞ
Here, I've prepared some coffee.
It'll warm you up.
Grandpa, how long have you been up here?
お爺さん いったい何時からここにいるのさ
明け方に目が覚めてみたら まだお前が帰っていないもんだから
When I woke up this morning, you weren't back yet.
久々に空でも眺めながら孫の朝帰りを待ってみようかと思ってな
So I thought I'd watch the sky while
waiting for my grandson to come home.
When you were little, we used to
come up here and stargaze all the time.
お前が小さい頃は何度もこうして一緒に星を眺めたなあ
覚えとるか
Do you remember?
Yeah, I do.
うん まあね
When Martha and I settled in Japan,
マーサと二人で日本に住む時は
we decided to build our house on higher ground in Miyama with a skylight we could use to access the roof.
住まいはこのミヤマの丘に建てて
必ず屋根に出られる天窓をつけようと決めていてな
こうしてお気に入りの屋根の上に座ってな
It's always been our dream to sit out here on our
beloved roof with our grandchildren to watch the stars.
孫と一緒に星を眺めるのが
昔からの夢だったんじゃ
We never thought we'd have the chance, though.
まさか叶うとは思わなかったが
本物の孫たちは この屋根に来てくれたことなんぞ一度もないよ
Our real grandchildren never once came out here.
儂が星を眺める時は いつも独りきりじゃった
Whenever I watched the stars, I was always alone.
Hey, Waver.
なあ ウェイバー
お前さん 儂らの孫ではないね
You're not our grandson, are you?
It's strange how Martha and I believed you were.
どうして儂もマーサもお前さんのことを孫だと信じ込んでいたのか不思議ではあるが
You were a little too nice to be our grandson.
お前さん 儂らの孫にしては ちょっと日頃から優しすぎたわなあ
怒って ないんですか
You're not mad?
まあ ここは怒って当然のところなのかもしれんがな
Well, maybe I should be angry.
But Martha's been really happy lately.
ここ最近マーサの奴が本当に愉しそうによく笑うようになってなあ
I wouldn't have imagined it before.
以前じゃ考えられんことじゃ
Really, I'm grateful to you two.
お前さん方に感謝したいぐらいでな
At any rate, it doesn't look like you're
staying here because you want to do us harm.
見たところ お前さん 儂らに何か悪さをしようと思って
この家に住み着いてるわけでもなさそうだしな
In fact, what do you think?
むしろ どうだろう
出来ることなら もうしばらくこのまま続けてほしいんだが
If possible, I'd like this to continue for a while longer.
I'm sorry...
申し訳ないけど
But I can't promise that.
約束はできません
I can't even guarantee I'll make it back here safely.
無事またここに帰ってこられる保証はないんで
So you two are risking your lives?
すると 命懸けなのかね お前さん方は
Yes.
はい
Well, I don't know how important what you're doing is to you.
それがお前さんにとって どれだけ大切な事柄なのかは分からんが
人生 長生きした後で振り返ってみればな
But when you look back after a long life,
you'll realize there's nothing really worth risking your life for.
命と秤にかけられるほどの事柄なんて
結局のところ一つもありはせんものじゃよ
最後に睡眠をとってから四十時間 というところか
It's been about forty hours since I last slept.
戦いを勝ち抜き 聖杯を降臨させるには
To win the war and summon the Grail, one must
perform the ritual at one of the four Fuyuki ley line areas.
冬木にある四つの霊脈の内いずれかで儀式を行わなければならない
At two of them, the church and the Tohsaka residence,
その内の二箇所 遠坂邸　聖堂教会にも言峰綺礼の姿はなかった
Kotomine Kirei was nowhere to be found.
となれば残り二つ
Which leaves the other two.
Here, at Mt. Enzou, or the Fuyuki City Hall.
ここ円蔵山か もしくは冬木市民会館
This is the more likely place,
considering their respective spiritualities.
霊格からいっておそらくここが最優力
Even if he chooses the City Hall, I can launch a frontal assault there.
万一市民会館であっても あそこならば正面から強襲をかければいい
If Maiya were still alive, I would've sent her to secure it.
舞弥が生きていれば 市民会館の方に回したんだがな
Once again, I'm alone.
また 独りになったな
Come to think of it, I didn't count her in.
そういえば あれを頭数に入れていなかったな
Since last night, I've been searching the entire city for Irisviel.
昨夜から 市街をくまなく巡ってアイリスフィールを捜しています
But I have found nothing.
が 依然手がかりもなく
申し訳ありません
I am deeply sorry.
では 何かあった時には以前のように令呪による召喚を
Well then. If you need me, use a Command Spell to summon me like you did before.
Woman.
女
Can you hear me, woman?
聞こえているか 女
言峰綺礼
Kotomine... Kirei.
This is where Caster's Master once hid.
ここはかつて キャスターのマスターが隠れ潜んでいた場所だ
Emiya Kiritsugu never managed to find it.
衛宮切嗣は最後まで探し出せなかったようだがな
Soon, the Grail War will come to its conclusion.
まもなく聖杯戦争は決着する
It's likely that I'll be the one to realize the wish of the Einzberns.
おそらくはこの私が アインツベルンの悲願を遂げる担い手となることだろう
私ではそんなに不満かね
Are you so unhappy that it would be me?
I would entrust the Grail to only one man.
私が聖杯を託すのはただ一人
断じてお前などではないわ
And that person isn't you, Executor.
代行者
Emiya Kiritsugu has already seen right through you.
お前の中身は 全て衛宮切嗣に見抜かれてるわ
彼はお前を最悪の敵と見なしている
He recognizes you as his greatest enemy.
Prepare yourself.
覚悟することね
That's good news to me.
それは私にとって福音だ
Emiya Kiritsugu is exactly as I had imagined, after all.
衛宮切嗣は やはり私が考えていた通りの男だったな
How laughable.
片腹痛いわね
誰よりも彼とは程遠い男のくせに
You couldn't be more different from him.
What?
何だと
While Kiritsugu can see through you, the reverse is impossible.
切嗣にお前が見抜けたとしても その逆は有り得ないわ
あの人の心に在るものを お前は何一つ持ち合わせてはいない
You have none of the things he carries in his heart.
なぜ貴様が私について語る
Why are you appraising me?
認めよう 確かに私は空虚な人間だ
I admit it.
I am an empty man.
However...
だが 私と奴とがどう違う
How do he and I differ?
All these years, he's thrown himself into battles with no conceivable gain.
永きに渡り何の益もない戦いにばかり身を投じ
He simply slaughtered over and over again.
ただ殺戮ばかりを繰り返してきた男が
His utter recklessness, the wasted effort!
あれほどの無軌道が 徒労が
If he isn't lost, then what is he?!
迷い人でなくて何なのだ
答えろ 衛宮切嗣は何を望んで聖杯を求める
Answer me.
What does Emiya Kiritsugu want from the Holy Grail?
What prayer would he ask of the wish-granting device?
奴が願望機に託す祈りとは 何だ
Very well.
いいわ 教えてあげる
I'll tell you.
衛宮切嗣の悲願は
Emiya Kiritsugu's wish...
人類の救済
He wishes for humanity's salvation,
the elimination of war and bloodshed.
あらゆる戦乱と流血の根絶
For eternal peace on Earth.
恒久的 世界平和よ
What was that?
なんだ それは
You can't possibly understand.
お前に分かるはずもない
That's the difference between him and you.
それがお前と彼との差 信念の有無よ
He has faith, and you don't.
Conflict is humanity's primal instinct.
闘争は人間の本性だ
Eliminating it would mean eliminating humanity itself.
それを根絶するというのなら 人間を根絶するも同然だ
It doesn't even work as an ideal.
そもそも 理想として成り立っていない
まるで子供の戯れ言だ
It's practically a childish joke!
That's why he has no choice but to hope for a miracle.
だからこそ 彼はとうとう奇跡に縋るしかなくなったのよ
Many times, he's been forced to
sacrifice his loved ones for his beliefs.
あの人は 追い求めた理想のために
常に愛する人を切り捨てる決断を迫られてきた
そう 切嗣は理想を追うには優しすぎる人
Yes...
He is too kind to chase ideals.
いずれ失うと分かっていても 愛さずにはいられない
He can't help but love others, despite knowing he'll eventually lose them...
I understand.
分かったよ
I understand very well.
よく分かった それが衛宮切嗣か
So that's Emiya Kiritsugu.
I can finally see...
ついに得たぞ 戦う意義を
...my reason to fight.
Emiya Kiritsugu.
衛宮切嗣 お前の理想を
I shall smash your ideals, and the Holy Grail, into smithereens right in front of you.
目の前で聖杯もろとも木っ端微塵に打ち砕いてやろう
おお 目が覚めたか 坊主
Oh, you're awake, boy?
I told you to wake me up when night had fallen.
夜になったら起こせって言っておいたのに
Why didn't you do that?
何やってんだ お前
Sorry, sorry.
すまんすまん
But I thought it might be a good idea to take
more time than usual with preparations tonight.
だがまあ 今夜はいつもほど焦らず
落ち着いて構えておこうと思ってな
Why?
何でさ
Well, it's just a feeling,
まあ 何となくな
今夜あたりに決着がつきそうな予感がするのだ
but I think everything will reach its conclusion tonight.
Right.
夜の空気が静かすぎる感じがする
The night air seems too still.
もう参加者も残り少なくなってるってことなのかな
Does that mean only a few participants remain?
ここからは本当に強い者たちばかりということだ
It means there will only be the strong from now on.
Wh-What was that?
な 今のは
妙な魔力の波動だったな
That's a strange mana surge.
I've experienced something similar before.
以前にも似たようなのがあったが
That pattern...
あのパターンは
What?
何だ 何かの符丁なのか
Is it some sort of code?
Four and seven, in different colors.
色違いで 四と七
達成と勝利だよな
"Victory" and "success".
Does the sending up of that signal mean the Grail War is over?
あんな狼煙を上げるってことは
まさか 聖杯戦争が決着したって意味なのか
No.
いや にしてもあっちは教会とは全然別の方角だ
It's in a different direction from the church.
教会の連中が上げた狼煙じゃないのか
So it wasn't the Church that sent the message?
In essence, someone is getting ahead of himself and declaring victory.
要するに 誰か気の早い奴が勝手に勝ち鬨を吼えとるわけだ
He's inviting anyone who objects to come get him.
文句があるならここに来いと
It's a challenge.
あれは挑発であろうよ
Tonight will likely be the final battle!
今夜は決戦の大一番となりそうだな
そうか これが 最後なんだな
I see.
This is it, then.
That's right!
応ともさ
And now that our battlefield is known, I must go forth in a way that will not shame the Rider class!
さあ 目指す戦場が定まったとあれば
余もまた騎手のクラスに恥じぬ形で
馳せ参じなくてはなるまいぞ
Come forth, my beloved steed!
出よ 我が愛馬
Now, boy.
さあ坊主 戦車と比べればちょいと荒れる乗り心地だが
The ride won't be as smooth as going by chariot... hmm?
What are you waiting for?
何をぐずぐずしておる ほれ
Come on.
ここからは本当に強い者しか行っちゃいけないんだろう
From this point, only the strong can continue, right?
我がサーヴァントよ ウェイバー·ベルベットが令呪をもって命ずる
My Servant.
By my Command Spell, I, Waver Velvet, order you.
Rider, fight until you gain victory.
ライダーよ 必ずや最後までお前が勝ち抜け
And by another Command Spell, I order you.
重ねて令呪をもって命ずる
Rider, win the Holy Grail.
ライダーよ 必ずお前が聖杯を掴め
And by yet another Command Spell, I order you.
さらに重ねて令呪で命ずる
Rider, conquer the world.
ライダーよ 世界を掴め
I won't accept failure.
失敗なんて許さない
Well, I'm no longer your Master or anything now.
さあ これで僕はもう お前のマスターでも何でもない
もう行けよ どこへなりとも行っちまえ
Go.
Go wherever.
お前なんか もう
You're no longer...
Sure, I'll be on my way.
もちろん すぐにでも行かせてもらうが
After giving me those annoying orders, surely you must be prepared to see them to the end.
あれだけ口喧しく命じた以上は
当然貴様も見届ける覚悟であろう
You idiot, you idiot!
馬鹿馬鹿馬鹿
Listen!
あのなあ 令呪ないんだぞ マスター辞めたんだぞ
I have no Command Spells!
I quit being your Master!
何でまだ僕を連れて行く
Why would you still take me with you?
I...
僕は
Master or not, you are my friend.
マスターじゃないにせよ
余の友であることに違いはあるまい
ぼ 僕が 僕なんかで
A-Are you...
Are you sure I'm worthy enough?
本当にいいのか
I can stay by your side?
お前なんかの隣で 僕が
What are you talking about? You've been through so many battles with me.
あれだけ余と共に戦場に臨んでおきながら 何を言うのだ
Idiot.
馬鹿者
貴様は今日まで 余と同じ敵に立ち向かってきた
Up until now, have you not faced the same enemies as I have?
That makes you my friend!
ならば友だ
So hold your chest high, and consider yourself...
胸を張って堂々と余に
比類せよ
...my equal.
さて ではまず第一の令呪に答えるとしようか
All right.
I shall begin by answering your first command.
Boy, open your eyes and watch to the end!
坊主 刮目して見届けよ
Yeah, do it!
ああ やってみろよ
Right before my eyes!
この僕の目の前で
In order to gain the initiative in battle,
he chose the place least suited to the ritual.
奴は戦いの主導権を握るためだけに
最も儀式に向かない場所を選んだ
In other words, his plan is not to secure the Grail,
つまりは 奴は聖杯そのものではなく
but to use it as bait to kill me and the other Masters.
聖杯を餌に
集まったマスターを 僕を
殺すことが目的だったと
That simplifies things.
ならば話は早い
If that's the best he could come up with, I'll just quickly eliminate him.
所詮奴がその程度の敵ならば
速やかに排除するのみ
Kotomine Kirei...
言峰綺礼
You're looking particularly ferocious tonight, Kirei.
今宵はまたいつになく猛々しい面構えではないか
綺礼
さて どうするのだ
Now, what will you do?
オレはここで待ちかまえていればいいと
Do you want me to wait here?
If your powers were released at close range, they could endanger the ceremony.
お前の力を間近で解放されたら
儀式そのものを危険に晒しかねん
If you want to fight at full strength, go out and meet them.
存分にやりたいというなら
迎撃に出てもらおう
Very well.
良かろう
But what if this place comes under attack while I'm away?
だが オレの留守にここを襲われた場合は
I'll use a Command Spell to save myself. Is that permissible?
その時は令呪の助けを借りるが 構わないかね
I shall allow it.
許す
ただし聖杯の安全までは保証せぬぞ
However, I can't guarantee the Grail's safety.
I won't be holding back tonight.
今宵のオレは手加減抜きでいく
That would be the worst outcome,
but if that ensues, it would be fate.
最悪の展開だが そうなればそれもまた運命だな
Kirei.
綺礼よ どうやら戦う意味については答を得た様子だが
You seem to have found your reason to fight,
今でもまだ聖杯に託す祈りはないのか
but do you still have no prayer to ask of the Grail?
やはり願いなど思いつかん
I can't think of anything I'd want.
If I had to answer, it'd be that nothing will interfere with this coming fight.
強いて言うなら
この戦いに余計な邪魔が入らないでほしいことくらいか
やれやれ やはりお前が心に秘めたモノは
Well, well.
As I suspected, the only recourse is to let the Grail reveal what you hide within your heart.
聖杯の側に汲み取らせるしかあるまいよ
ああ もし仮にオレが戻るより先にセイバーが現れるようなら
Oh.
If Saber appears here before I return,
have Berserker entertain her for a while.
しばらくバーサーカーと戯れさせてやるがいい
承知した
Understood.
Speaking of Saber, what happened to
the doll she was trying so hard to protect?
セイバーと言えば
あれが後生大事に守っていた人形めはどうした
Doesn't the Grail vessel reside within her?
聖杯の器とやらはあれの中にあるのであろう
I killed her.
殺したよ 生かしておく必要もなかったのでな
I couldn't find a reason to keep her alive.
Are you crying, Mommy?
泣いているの お母様
Mommy, I had a really scary dream.
ねえ お母様 怖い夢を見たの
イリヤが杯になっちゃう夢を
I dreamed that I became a cup...
イリヤの中にね ものすごく大きなカタマリが七つも入ってくるの
...and seven really big lumps appeared inside me...
It's okay... it's okay.
大丈夫 大丈夫よ
I won't let that happen.
決してそんなことにはさせない
あなたがそれを見ることはないわ イリヤ
That will never happen to you, Ilya.
I'm sure the chains of fate will release you.
あなたはきっと運命の枷から解き放たれる
Is this place...
ここは
...inside the Grail?
聖杯の中
That can't be!
そんなはずは
Then...
じゃあ ここにいる私は
If I'm in here...
誰
...who am I?
I see.
ああ そう
This is inside the Holy Grail.
ここは聖杯の中
The omnipotent wishing device that will dispel all the world's sorrows and erase all suffering.
万能の願望器がこの世の全ての嘆きを刈り取り
全ての苦悩を取り払う
I'll have the power to make that happen.
叶える力が手に入る
終わりは もうすぐそこまできているわ
The end is almost at hand.
Episode 22
All the World's Evil
Doushite sora wa konnani aokute
どうして空はこんなに青くて
Why is the sky so blue?
Nanimo kanashimi wo shiranu you ni
何も悲しみを知らぬように
As if oblivious to sadness
Itsumo tamerawazu ashita e to kuzureochiru
いつも躊躇わず明日へと崩れ落ちる
It crumbles incessantly to make way for a new day
Inochi wa tarinai mama umarete kuru no ne
命は足りないまま生まれてくるのね
I suppose we are born with our lives short
Kakeochita kokoro ni anata ga furete
かけおちた心にあなたが触れて
You have touched my torn heart
Futari de yuku mirai wa kegare no nai tsuyosa de
二人で行く未来は穢れのない強さで
Our future ahead is filled with a pure, unblemished strength
Sora wa takaku kaze wa utau
空は高く 風は歌う
The sky is vast, the wind is melody
Yume wo miteta yorokobi e to
夢を見てた喜びへと
Men will one day come to realize
Hito wa itsuka tadoritsukeru
人はいつか辿り着ける
The joy of chasing after a dream
Kodomo no hitomi de anata wa shinjita
子供の瞳であなたは信じた
With the eyes of a child, you've always had faith
Soba ni iru yo
そばにいるよ
I'll be right beside you
Kooritsuita mori wo nukete
凍りついた森を抜けて
As we pass through the frozen forest
Sono hitomi ga sekai no nageki ni mayowanu you ni
その瞳が世界の嘆きに迷わぬように
So that the world's sorrow will not taint your eyes
Our enemy is the mighty King of Heroes.
敵は万夫不当の英雄王
A worthy opponent!
相手にとって不足なし
Let us show him our path of conquest!
我らが覇道を示そうぞ
King of Conquerors, you will learn of
the conclusion to your endless dream.
征服王 見果てぬ夢の結末を知るがいい
I'll personally show you how things are.
このオレが手ずから理を示そう
Next Episode
The Sea at the World's Edge